Finding Aid for American Gold Star Mothers, inc. Washtenaw County Chapter records, 1950-1975
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
American Gold Star Mothers, inc. Washtenaw County Chapter records 1950-1975
American Gold Star Mothers, inc. Washtenaw County Chapter.
1 linear foot.
8521 Be 2
Organization of mothers of servicemen who died in action. Minute books, scrapbooks, photographs, citations and certificate of service, and miscellanea.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came to the library in 1977 through Elsie Allen and Mrs. Gordon E. Smith (Donor no. 6002 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Gold Star Mothers is an organization of women who lost a son or daughter while serving in the military.
The record group consists of minute books, 1950-1975; scrapbooks, 1950-1968; and miscellaneous other materials, including scattered photographs.
Subjects:
Women--Michigan--Washtenaw County--Societies and clubs.; Washtenaw County (Mich.).
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Buildings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Hospitals--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Rites and ceremonies.; Veterans Administration Hospital (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Washtenaw County (Mich.)--Social life and customs.; Women--Michigan--Washtenaw County--Societies and clubs.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Minute books, 1950-1975
  - September 1950-March 1956 (Box 1)
  - April 1956-March 1962 (Box 1)
  - November 1963-September 1973 (Box 1)
  - December 1973-May 1975 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks, 1950-1968
  - Scrapbook, 1950-1953, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1953-1955 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1955-1958 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1958-1968 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous minutes and other records (Box 1)
  - Citations and certificates of service (Box 1)
  - Clippings of death notices of Washtenaw servicemen during World War II and the Vietnam war [Sample] (Box 1)
  - Photographs of organizational activities, especially chapter meetings, social events, and national conventions. (Box 1)